[SOUND] Hello,
你好
welcome to the course in Text and Retrieval and Search Engines.
欢迎来到文本检索和搜索引擎课程。
I'm ChengXiang Zhia.
我是 ChengXiang Zhai。
I have a nickname Cheng.
我有个昵称叫 Cheng。
I'm a Professor of the Department of Computer Science at the University of
我是伊利诺伊大学厄巴纳－香槟分校
Illinois at Urbana-Champaign.
我是UIUC的物理学教授Nigel Goldenfeld
This first lecture is basically an introduction to the course,
第一讲主要是课程内容的
a brief introduction to what we will cover in the course.
简要介绍。
We're going to first talk about the data mining specialization seeing this course
我们先讲解数据挖掘专项项目
is part of that specialization.
因为这门课程是此项目的一部分。
And then we will cover motivation objectives of the course,
然后我们介绍这门课程的学习目标和动机，
this will be followed by prerequisites and course format and reference books.
之后是对已有知识的要求，课程形式和参考书目。
And then finally, we will talk about the course schedule,
最后，我们介绍授课计划，
which has a number of topics to be covered in the rest of this course.
它包含接下来的课程中讲授的几个主题。
So the data mining specialization offered by the University of Illinois at
由UIUC大学提供的数据挖掘专项
Urbana-Champaign is really to address the need for their mining techniques
是用来满足利用数据挖掘技术解决大数据问题
to handle a lot of big data, to turn the big data into knowledge.
并把大数据转化为知识的需求。
There are five lecture-based courses,
有五门授课形式的课程
as you see on the slide, plus one capstone project in the end.
加上结尾的毕业设计。
I'm teaching two of them, which is this course, Text Retrieval and
我将讲授其中的两门，即文本检索
Search Engines, and this one.
搜索引擎以及这个
The two courses that I cover here are all about text data.
这两门课都是关于文本信息的。
In contrast, the other courses are covering more general
相比之下，其他的课程覆盖面更广
techniques that can be applied to all kinds of data.
它们可以应用于各种形式的信息。
So pattern discovery, taught by Professor Jiawei Han, and
由Han Jiawei教授讲解的模式识别和聚类分析
cluster analysis, again taught by him, about the general data mining
是关于通用数据挖掘技术的，
techniques to handle structured and unstructured text data.
它们能够处理结构化和非结构化的文本数据。
And data visualization covered by Professor John Hart, is about the general
由John Hart教授主讲的数据可视化
visualization techniques, again, applicable to all kinds of data.
是关于适用于所有数据的通用数据可视化技术。
So the motivation for this course, in fact, also for
本课程和我所讲的另外课程的动机是
the other courses that I'm teaching, is that we have a lot of text data and
我们有海量的文本数据，
the data is everywhere, is growing rapidly.
它们无处不在，且正在快速增加。
So you must have been experiencing this growth.
你肯定已经感受到了这种增长。
Just think about how much text data you're dealing with every day,
想一下你每天要处理多少文本数据，
I list some date types here.
以及这里的这些数据类型
For example, on the Internet we see a lot of web pages, news articles, etc.,
例如，我们在互联网上看到很多网页、新闻、文章等
and then we have blog articles, emails,
我们还有博客文章、电子邮件
scientific literature, and tweets.
科研文献和推特
As we are speaking, maybe a lot of tweets are being written, and
我们正在说话的时候，就有大量的微博在被编写，
a lot of emails are being sent.
大量的电子邮件正被发送。
So, the amount of text data is beyond our capacity to understand, then.
文本信息的数量超过我们的理解能力。
Also, the amount of data makes it possible to actually analyze the data to
并且，如此大的数据量使通过分析数据
discover interesting knowledge.
来识别我们感兴趣的知识成为可能。
And that's what we meant by harnessing big text data.
这就是我们所指的利用文本大数据的含义。
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community